Guide to the Edward James Brown
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Edward J. Brown Papers
1946-1991
SC0500
Brown, Edward James, 1909-1991
50 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of the trust of Catherine C. Brown, 1995.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical History
Edward James Brown was a pioneer in the academic study of Russian literature in the United States. Brown received his bachelor's and master's degrees from the University of Chicago and his Ph.D. from Columbia University. He joined the faculty at Brown University in 1947, where he established the undergraduate and graduate programs in Slavic Studies. He left Brown in 1965 to teach at Indiana University. In the late 1960s he was also president of the American Association of Teachers of Slavic and Eastern European Languages and of the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1970; he retired in 1975 but continued to teach. He died in 1991.
His published works included The Proletarian Episode in Russian Literature, 1928-1932 (1953, 1971), Russian Literature Since the Revolution (1982), and Mayakovsky: A Poet in the Revolution (1973). He directed the Summer Seminar on Soviet Literature and Society, held at Stanford in 1986.
Description of the Collection
These papers, dating from 1946 to 1991, pertain primarily to his teaching and research at Brown, Indiana, and Stanford Universities and include correspondence, his manuscripts and typescripts, course materials, research notes, and his published works. There are also materials pertaining to the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, works by other scholars and students, and photographs, including images of Vladimir Mayakovsky and of Moscow. Some materials are in Russian. These papers are partially processed. The correspondence files have been separated and the various chronological arrangements that Brown used were interfiled. These papers were then refoldered and reboxed and an index was prepared. The remaining papers have not yet been processed, but are available. They are in Boxes IB through 26B and 27 through 36 and have only box descriptions, not folder listings. Both listings also exist in database form and can be searched. Please see the reference staff for assistance.
Access Terms
Berliner, Joseph S.; Brown, Deming, 1919-1999; Brown, Edward James, 1909-1991; Chukovskiĭ, Korneĭ, 1882-1969.; Dovlatov, Sergei.; Dunham, Vera Sandomirsky, 1912-2001; Edgerton, William Benbow, 1914-; Fanger, Donald.; Garrard, John Gordon.; Gibian, George.; Ginzburg, Lidii͡a, 1902-1990.; Jakobson, Roman, 1896-1982.; Kharon, IA (IAkov), 1914-; Mayakovsky, Vladimir, 1893-1930.; McLean, Hugh, 1925-; Olcott, Anthony Charles.; Proffer, Carl R.; Treadgold, Donald W., 1922-; American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies.; Brown University--Faculty.; Russian literature--20th century--History and criticism.; Slavic literature--History and criticism.; Stanford University--Faculty.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - AAASS, 1960 - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AAASS, 1964 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AAASS Correspondence, 1964 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AAASS Correspondence, 1963 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AAASS Correspondence: Board Meetings and Elections (incl. Publications Business), 1964 - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AAASS Correspondence: Board of Directors Meeting, 1964 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AAASS Correspondence: Treasurer's Reports, 1963 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AAASS Correspondence: Miscellaneous, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AAASS Correspondence: 1967 National Convention, 1967 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACLS Committee on Slavic Publications, 1964 - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence A, 1956 - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence A, 1957 - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - A Correspondence, 1966 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - A Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - A Correspondence, 1974 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A Correspondence, 1980 - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - A Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Edward 1. Brown (regarding his professional appointments), 1946 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Edward 1. Brown (regarding his professional appointments), 1946 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - E.1. Brown - Russian Trip, 1963, 1963 - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - E.l. Brown, 1965 - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brown Family Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - B Correspondence: Beebe Case, 1965 - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - B Correspondence: Barton Road, 1979 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - B Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - B Correspondence, 1957 - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - B Correspondence, 1968 - 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - B Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - B Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - B Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - B Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - B Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - B Correspondence, 1980 - 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - B Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - C Correspondence: Cadley, 1965 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - C Correspondence: Collier Books, 1962 - 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - C Correspondence: Collier Books, 1968 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - C Correspondence: Columbia University - misc. corr. and ephemera, 1946 - 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - C Correspondence: Columbia University - misc. corr. and ephemera, 1946 - 1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - C Correspondence: Current Digest of the Soviet Press, 1968 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - C Correspondence, 1946 - 1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - C Correspondence, 1953 - 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - C Correspondence, 1957 - 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - C Correspondence, 1965 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - C Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - C Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - C Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - C Correspondence, 1975 - 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - C Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - C Correspondence, 1982 - 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - C Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - D Correspondence: Dissertation Proposals, 1970 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - D Correspondence: Dulley, Bryan E., 1966 - 1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - D Correspondence: Dunham, Vera S., 1965 - 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - D Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - D Correspondence, 1957 - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - D Correspondence, 1965 - 1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - D Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - D Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - D Correspondence, 1975 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - D Correspondence, 1979 - 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - D Correspondence, 1981 - 1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - D Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - E Correspondence, 1956 - 1959 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - E Correspondence, 1962 - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - E Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - E Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - E Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - E Correspondence, 1975 - 1980 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - E Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - E Correspondence, 1983 - 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - E Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - F Correspondence: Falen, James, 1970 - 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - F Correspondence: Fanger, Donald, 1965 - 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - F Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - F Correspondence, 1958 - 1959 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - F Correspondence, 1964 - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - F Correspondence, 1969 - 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - F Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - F Correspondence, 1975 - 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - F Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - F Correspondence, 1981 - 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - F Correspondence, 1989 - 1900 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - G Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - G Correspondence, 1959 - 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - G Correspondence, 1966 - 1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - G Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - G Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - G Correspondence, 1974 - 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - G Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - G Correspondence, 1981 - 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - G Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - H Correpsondence: Harkins, William, 1967 - 1968 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - H Correspondence: Harvard University Press, 1980 - 1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - H Correspondence: Health, Education, and Welfare, 1978 - 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - H Correspondence: Humanities Center, 1987 - 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - H Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - H Correspondence, 1958 - 1960 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - H Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - H Correspondence, 1975 - 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - H Correspondence, 1976 - 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - H Correspondence, 1981 - 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - H Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - I Correspondence: Indiana University Press, 1967 - 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - I Correspondence: IREX, 1968 - 1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - I Correspondence: IREX, 1977 - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - I Correspondence: IREX, 1978 - 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - I Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - I Correspondence, 1958 - 1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - I Correspondence, 1966 - 1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - I Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - I Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - I Correspondence, 1975 - 1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - I Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - I Correspondence, 1979 - 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - I Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - J Correspondence: Joint Committee on Slavic Studies, 1969 - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - J Correspondence, 1958 - 1958 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - J Correspondence, 1965 - 1966 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - J Correspondence, 1969 - 1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - J Correspondence, 1972 - 1987 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - J Correspondence, 1974 - 1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - J Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - K Correspondence: Kassoff, Allen, 1978 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - K Correspondence: Kennan Institute, 1978 - 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - K Correspondence: Komman, 1971 - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - K Correspondence: References and Recommendations, 1965 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - K Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - K Correspondence, 1958 - 1961 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - K Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - K Correspondence, 1969 - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - K Correspondence, 1974 - 1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - K Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - K Correspondence, 1975 - 1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - K Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - K Correspondence, 1982 - 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - K Correspondence, 1989 - 1900 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - L Corresspondence: EJB Lectures 1966-, 1966 - 1968 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - L Correspondence: Library (Stanford), 1970 - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - L Correspondence: Lopez-Morillas Case (1967), 1967 - 1967 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - L Correspondence, 1949 - 1957 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - L Correspondence, 1958 - 1959 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - L Correspondence, 1966 - 1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - L Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - L Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - L Correspondence, 1975 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - L Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - L Correspondence, 1981 - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - L Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - M Correspondence: Mayakovsky research, 1974 - 1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - M Correspondence: Mouton & Co., 1966 - 1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - M Correspondence, 1951 - 1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - M Correspondence, 1957 - 1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - M Correspondence, 1965 - 1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - M Correspondence, 1966 - 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - M Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - M Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - M Correspondence, 1973 - 1980 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - M Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - M Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - M Correspondence, 1982 - 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - M Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - N Correspondence: Nabokov Review, 1965 - 1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - N Correspondence: The Nation, 1967 - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - N Correspondence: New York Times Letter - responses, 1971 - 1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - N Correspondence, 1946 - 1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - N Correspondence, 1958 - 1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - N Correspondence, 1966 - 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - N Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - N Correspondence, 1974 - 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - N Correspondence, 1984 - 1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - N Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - O Correspondence: Offers, 1969 - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - O Correspondence: Overseas Campuses, 1972 - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - O Correspondence: Oxford University Press, 1968 - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - O Correspondence: Oxford University Press, 1971 - 1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - O Correspondence, 1958 - 1960 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - O Correspondence, 1965 - 1970 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - O Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - O Correspondence, 1974 - 1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - O Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - O Correspondence, 1982 - 1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - O Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - P Correspondence: Pappenheim Suit, 1964 - 1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - P Correspondence: Pekurovskaya, Asya, 1975 - 1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - P Correspondence: Pekurovskaya, Asya, 1979 - 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - P Correspondence: Pekurovskaya, Asya, 1981 - 1982 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - P Correspondence: Princeton University Press, 1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - P Correspondence: Princeton University Press, 1972 - 1975 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - P Correspondence: Princeton University Press, 1978 - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - P Correspondence: The Proletarian Episode in Russian Literature, 1953 - 1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - P Correspondence: Publications, Misc., 1967 - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - P Correspondence, 1958 - 1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - P Correspondence, 1966 - 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - P Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - P Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - P Correspondence, 1974 - 1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - P Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - P Correspondence, 1975 - 1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - P Correspondence, 1983 - 1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - P Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Q Correspondence, 1971 - 1971 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Q Correspondence, 1986 - 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - R Correspondence: Committee on Russian and East European Studies, 1970 - 1971 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - R Correspondence: Random House, 1962 - 1966 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - R Correspondence: The Russian Review, 1968 - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - R Correspondence, 1947 - 1957 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - R Correspondence, 1958 - 1960 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - R Correspondence, 1963 - 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - R Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - R Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - R Correspondence, 1975 - 1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - R Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - R Correspondence, 1982 - 1987 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - R Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - S Correspondence: Search Committee, 1974 - 1974 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - S Correspondence: Slavic and East European Journal, 1967 - 1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - S Correspondence: Slavic and East European Journal, 1969 - 1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - S Correspondence: Slavic Department Stanford, 1970 - 1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - S Correspondence: Slavic Review, 1966 - 1970 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - S Correspondence: Social Science Research Council, 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - S Correspondence: The Soviet System & Democratic Society, 1967 - 1968 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - S Correspondence: Stanford, 1961 - 1971 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - S Correspondence: Stanford Conference on Literature, 1970 - 1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - S Correspondence: Stanford University Press, 1965 - 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - S Correspondence, 1947 - 1952 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - S Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - S Correspondence, 1956 - 1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - S Correspondence, 1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - S Correspondence, 1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - S Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - S Correspondence, 1973 - 1974 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - S Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - S Correspondence, 1975 - 1979 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - S Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - S Correspondence, 1981 - 1989 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - S Correspondence, 1989 - 1900 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - T Correspondence: William Todd Promotion, 1983 - 1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - T Correspondence, 1956 - 1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - T Correspondence, 1962 - 1970 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - T Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - T Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - T Correspondence, 1971 - 1980 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - T Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - T Correspondence, 1975 - 1975 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - T Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - T Correspondence, 1981 - 1986 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - T Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - U Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - U Correspondence, 1958 - 1966 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - U Correspondence, 1974 - 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - U Correspondence, 1989 - 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - U Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - V Correspondence: Van Campen Promotion, 1970 - 1971 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - V Correspondence: Voprosy Literatury, 1967 - 1967 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - V Correspondence, 1946 - 1975 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - V Correspondence, 1956 - 1959 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - V Correspondence, 1965 - 1966 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - V Correspondence, 1975 - 1978 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - V Correspondence, 1982 - 1989 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - W Correspondence, 1956 - 1961 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - W Correspondence, 1965 - 1970 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - W Correspondence, 1969 - 1969 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - W Correspondence, 1969 - 1971 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - W Correspondence, 1974 - 1988 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - W Correspondence, 1976 - 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - W Correspondence, 1985 - 1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - W Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Y Correspondence, 1956 - 1969 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Y Correspondence, 1983 - 1987 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Z Correspondence, 1964 - 1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Z Correspondence, 1969 - 1975 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Z Correspondence, 1982 - 1984 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Sympathy Cards and letters from colleagues, 1991 - 1991 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Sympathy Cards and letters from colleagues, 1991 - 1991 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1947 - 1983 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Russian letters, 1968 - 1988 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Misc. salary and royalty papers, 1965 - 1977 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing letters, miscellaneous, 1959 - 1986 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Incoming letters, unidentified (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (non-correspondence) (Box 19)
  - (Box 1B)
    1. Articles by others (colleagues; students), mostly typescript; sometimes with accompanying letter
    2. Formalism-Structuralism course - lecture notes, syllabi, articles, student papers, 1974-1990
  - (Box 2B)
    1. Letter and article from Maximilian Br.
    2. Course files - lecture notes, syllabi, articles, student papers, etc., 1984-1990
  - (Box 3B)
    1. Course files (on Russian authors) - lecture notes, syllabi, articles, student papers, etc., 1958-1990
    2. Student papers and tests, 1948-1950
    3. Mathewson, Rufus, ph.d. thesis, Columbia 1954
    4. One miscellaneous file
  - (Box 4B)
    Course files and/or research files "B" - "T" 1955-1982 (includes more mss lectures and notes by Brown than in boxes 2 and 3)
  - (Box 5B)
    1. Course files: Slavic 220 Translation, 1980s
    2. Assorted files - Bibilographies in Russian; book review Brown
  - 1988 - 1990 (Box 6B)
    Works by Brown, 1988-1990 - articles, talks, reviews, etc., with some related correspondence and some lecture notes
  - 1985 - 1990 (Box 7B)
    Works by Brown, 1985-1990 - articles, talks, reviews, etc.; includes a few short stories
  - circa 1955 - 1956 (Box 8B)
    Miscellaneous files - typescript articles, his student notebooks and papers, papers by his students, lecture outline, report on sabbatical year 1955-56, class materials, biographical file
  - (Box 9B)
    1. Materials for new chapter in RUSSIAN LITERATURE SINCE THE REVOLUTION
    2. Miscellaneous files - articles by others, course readings, xeroxed articles annotated by Brown
  - (Box 10B)
    Materials used for Formalism and Structuralism course - xeroxed articles, reprints, typescript articles, notes, class handouts and a copy of Vasily Grossman's LIFE AND FATE, annotated by Brown
  - 1969 - 1986 (Box 11B)
    Miscellaneous papers, 1969-1986: course materials; correspondence files from seminar on Soviet Literature and Society (1986); subject files; notes
  - 1984 - 1986 (Box 12B)
    Papers and articles by others, unpublished, 1984-86 and undated; some in Russian
  - (Box 13B)
    Papers and articles by others, unpublished
  - (Box 14B)
    Manuscripts, typescripts, and galleys of works by Brown
  - (Box 15B)
  - (Box 16B)
  - 1960 - 1974 (Box 17B)
    American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies files, 1960-74: newsletters, correspondence, reports, memos, papers
  - (Box 18B)
    Miscellaneous files
  - (Box 19B)
    Dissertation chapters and book typescripts by others
  - (Box 20B)
    Note cards
  - (Box 21B)
  - (Box 22B)
    1. Note cards
    2. Manuscripts and typescripts of book chapters
    3. Typescript book by William Mills Todd ("Early Russian Novels and Polite Society")
  - circa 1980 - 1986 (Box 23B)
    1. Typescripts, manuscripts, page proofs of talks, articles, and reviews by Brown, with some related correspondence, 1980-86
    2. Typescript book by S. Foster Damon ("What Shakspere Said")
  - circa 1953 - 1963 (Box 24B)
    1. Brown's Russian Literature Since the Revolution - first draft, typescript copies, page proofs, 1963 and earlier
    2. Brown's Proletarian Episode in Russian Literature - typescript copies, correspondence with publisher 1953
  - (Box 25B)
    1. Brown's Proletarian Episode in Russian Literature - typescript copy and galleys
    2. Brown's Russian Literature Since the Revolution - galleys
    3. Brown's Stankevich and His Moscow Circle - typescripts
  - (Box 26B)
    1. Works by others
    2. Martin Kaplan - dissertation and correspondence
  - (Box 27)
    1. Typescript of Brown's dissertation, with some notes and outlines (was unfoldered; broken into folders arbitrarily)
    2. Translations and/or papers by Brown (or possibly his students)
    3. Some works by others
  - (Box 28)
    l. Catherine Brown's files on "Persephone in Hell" by S. Foster Damon
    2. Photos of Vladimir Mayakovsky
    3. Files on Vladimir Mayakovsky